# SAYED SOHAN

House no-7/6, Block-C, Biswas Betka, Tangail-1900 +8801701135549 ♦ ssohan.mbstu@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/ssohan/

## **SUMMARY**

As a Senior Software Engineer at one of Bangladesh's top companies, I bring around 2 years of professional experience in an Agile-Scrum environment. My technical expertise spans .NET, C#, SQL (Backend), as well as HTML, CSS, and jQuery (Frontend). My inquisitive and flexible nature ensures that I am always eager to learn and adapt to new challenges.

# **EDUCATION**

Mawlana Bhashani Science and Technology University, Tangail

Jan 2016 - Nov 2021

Bachelor's (BSc. Engg.) in Computer Science and Engineering

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Enosis Solutions, Dhaka**

April 2023- Present

Senior Software Engineer

- Developing maintainable code by following Onion Architecture and SOLID principle.
- Analyzing Research and Development (R&D) intensive task.
- Maintaining Security, Performance, Resiliency, and Best Practices.
- Reviewing codes, planning sprints, and handling issues.

#### **Enosis Solutions, Dhaka**

July 2021- March 2023

Software Engineer

- Experienced in enterprise-level software development with Agile Scrum.
- Migrated and maintained project from VB.net to ASP.NET Core 6.
- Analyzed, estimated, reported, managed & implemented Jira Ticket.
- Technologies used: ASP.NET Core, Agile/Scrum, REST API, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Jira, Azure DevOps, MSSQL-2016.

## TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

- Software Frameworks: ASP.NET Core and MVC
- Programming Languages: C#, Javascript, ¡Query, HTML, CSS, C++
- Database Technologies: SQL, MS-SQL, MongoDB
- Tools: Git, Jira, Visual Studio, Source Tree

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals
- Achieved HackerRank Problem Solving (Advanced) Certification

## **EXTRACURRICULAR**

- Was a member of Bangladesh Scouts.
- Arranged and Attended many online/onsite competitive programming contests.

UVa: 385+ Solves

Problem Solving & Ratings: Codeforces: 1545 (max rating)

Stackoverflow: 1330+